《越狱》前情回顾
Previously on Prison Break
孩子 我对你没什么成见
I got nothing against you, kid.
你要做什么?
What are you doing, man?
但是子弹有
But they do.
你们的好朋友曼彻告诉了我有关
Your pal manche told me all about your little treasure hunt
搜寻韦斯特莫兰德藏款的计划
for Westmoreland's stash.
我们出发去犹他州
We're going to Utah.
傻瓜
Fooled you.
把手放在背后
Hands behind your back.
-你随意好了 -好的
-Make yourself at home. -Sure.
你父亲接到了通白宫打来的电话
Your father got a call from the White House.
撤销了你父亲的候选提名
They withdrew his nomination.
根据他们的说法 你父亲的批准程序有些问题
According to them, his confirmation was going to be a problem.
我爸爸不会自杀的
My father is not a suicidal man.
唐克雷蒂州长不在我们计划之内
Governor Tancredi, not part of our plan.
任何知道蛛丝马迹的人都不能放过
Anyone who knows anything has got to be dealt with.
如果有人成了累赘  就干掉他们
If someone's a liability, they go.
唐克雷蒂就是个累赘
Tancredi was becoming a liability.
他女儿也是
So was his daughter.
等等  什么?
Wait, what?
布伦斯按计划将于
Burrows is scheduled to be released
明日在其关押地亚利桑那州的
from the Klipton Detention Center in Kingman, Arizona
克利普顿拘留中心被释放
tomorrow morning.
LJ释放出来了 我要去接他
LJ is out there;I'm going to get him.
保重
Take care.
查尔斯 韦斯特莫兰德...
Charles Westmoreland...
愿上帝保佑你  还有你的破麻袋
god bless you and your wrinkled old sack.
全在这儿了
It's all here.
苏克雷在哪?
Where's Sucre?
放下包
Drop the bag.
谁都不许走
No one's going anywhere.
你他妈的在搞什么鬼?
What the hell are you doing, man?
苏克雷 不论你想要什么
Sucre...whatever it is you want...
我要钱  所有的钱
I want the money, all of it.
什么  你要抢我们的钱?
What, are you robbing us?
钱本来就不是你们的
The money was never yours to begin with.
这只是一个交易
This is about business.
500万美金值得我搏一记
$5 million worth of business.
这就是我们共患难的结果?
So this is how it's going to go down, huh?
我们共同经历了所有的事
After everything.
贼就是江山易改本性难移
Once a thief, always a thief.
你才意识到啊?
You just figuring that out?
给我背包
The backpack.
快!
Now!
兄弟  别这么做
Don't do this, buddy.
小子  你自己好好合计一下
Yo, take a look around you, papi.
我们有三个人而你只孤身一人
It's three of us, it's one of you
难道这笔帐你不会算 我们会一直追你到天涯海角
you are outnumbered, man, and we will come after you.
兄弟  这可能是你能做的最后一件事了
It'll be the last thing you do, my brother.
你打算把我们都打死?
What, are you going to shoot at all of us?
也许不会
Probably not.
但是我可以打死两个
but I will get two.
现在...
Now...
谁想成为那两个呢?
which two is it going to be?
这就对了
That's what I thought.
再见  朋友们
Adios, amigos.
我真不敢相信
I don't believe this.
我们历经艰险 好不容易光明就在眼前
We have come all this way and done all of this work.
纹身小子  你们不还是好兄弟吗?
Thought you was compadres, tattoo?
伙计们  那我们现在怎么办
so what are we going to do now, man?
警察随时都会到
The police are going to be here any second.
我绝不能容忍那傻大个带着
Ain't no way I'm letting that- that dunderpate
五百万跑了…
ride off with five...
你们自己决定吧
It's your choice.
放心没什么事
It's all right.
别担心  给你这个  然后...
all right, I'm going to give you this, and, uh...
大约一个小时后你就可以
you should be able to cut yourself free
割断绳子重获自由
in about an hour.
伙计  你有什么计划?
So what's the plan, man?
你想做什么都行
Well, you can do what you want.
我让帝博格那个变态逃过一次
I let that psychopath t-bag loose once.
我不会再让他逃脱惩罚
I'm not going to do it again.
警察来的时候给他们留个小礼物
Make a nice little present for the police when they get here.
他哪儿去了?
Where is he?
我不知道
I don't know
伙计  我也该…我也该走了
man, look, I got to, I got to go.
好运
Uh, good luck.
他们会抓到你的
They're going to get you.
唐克雷蒂小姐
Ms.Tancredi.
我并不想吓到你
I didn't mean to startle you.
该死的  你在我屋里干什么?
What the hell are you doing in my house?
没什么好怕的
No reason to be frightened.
我以前和你父亲一起工作
I used to work with your father.
对你父亲的死我深表遗憾
I'm so sorry for your loss.
我父亲不是自杀的
My father didn't commit suicide.
你在干什么?
What are you doing?
让人确信我没像之前那样吸毒
Making sure it doesn't look like I did!
如果州长自杀的当天
People will ask questions
他女儿也被发现死于非命 现场还留有搏斗痕迹
if the day the governor was found killing himself
那么人们肯定会产生疑惑
his daughter is found dead in what looks like a struggle.
那么  好吧
Well, then.
如果他们找不到她呢?
What if they don't find her?
很明显州长的女儿为了避免牢狱之灾
In an apparent attempt to avoid jail time,
在保释中逃走并消失了
the governor's daughter skips bail and disappears.
我们在说你最后的几分钟  唐克雷蒂小姐
We're talking about your last minutes, Ms.Tancredi.
别这么做
Please don't do this.
桌子上的东西非常昂贵
That stuff on that table is premium.
A等品
It's grade "A".
帮你自己个忙
Do yourself a favor
出去享受一下
go out on a high.
我求求你
Look, I'm begging you here.
最后的盛宴
One last ride.
哦  妈的!
Oh, god!
"再见 朋友们"嗯?
Adios, amigos, huh?
怎么?  演过头了?
What? Too much?
干得漂亮
You were great.
老兄  这东西真他妈的重
this thing is freaking heavy, dude.
分了它就不会这么重了
Won't be so bad after we split it up.
3个人分  我  你  还有林肯
Three ways: Me, you and Linc.
是4个
Four.
我们得分给查尔斯的女儿一部分
We're going to send a share to Charles's daughter
并捎上他父亲给她的爱
with her father's love
正如之前承诺的那样
just like we promised.
富兰克林怎么办?
What about C-Note?
我总觉得整件事有点不太好
I feel kind of bad about the whole thing.
我们没法知道该不该信任他
There's no way to know if we could trust him.
等我们到了巴拿马
Once we get down to Panama
我们再往他家里汇些钱吧
we'll send something up to his family
确保他能过好点
make sure he's taken care of.
500万美金
Five million dollars.
我真不敢相信  我就要成为...
I can't believe I'm going to be...
见鬼钱到哪去了?
where the hell is the money?
Where the hell is the money?
背包...快!
The backpack...Now!
出售汽车
for sale by owner
布伦斯先生?
Mr.Burrows?
恭喜你出来!
Merry christmas from the state.
这张清单上有居住及招工信息可供选择
Here's a list of options available to you.
有些公司更愿意雇一些出狱的人
Places to stay, businesses that are more open to hiring.....
对你即将面对的未来有什么问题吗?
Any questions you might have about your immediate future?
没有
No.
好吧  这上面的电话是免费的
Well, the number on there is toll-free.
遇到任何问题随时都可以打这个电话
If you encounter any problems, you can call there 24-7.
-谢谢  -等下
-Thanks. Wait a second.
你知道吗?
You know what?
为什么不告诉我你要去哪呢？
Why don't you tell me where you need to go
我可以载你过去
and I'll make sure you get there.
行了  我没事的
You know, I think I'll be all right.
你确定?
You sure?
是的  谢谢
Yeah.Thank you.
孩子没上钩
Kid didn't bite.
他步行的
He's on foot
好吧
All right.
派人跟着他
Have your men follow.
记住我们要找的是他爸爸
Remember, it's the father we want.
我们不可以回去
We can't go back.
你说过  没钱我们就完蛋了
You said it, without the money, we're screwed.
我们不能...让我想想
We can't... just let me think.
或许还在...让我想想!让我想想!
- Maybe it's still back... - Just let me think! Let me think.
或许钱还在屋里
Maybe it's still back at the house.
钱不在屋里
The money's not back at the house
除非帝博格还在那儿
unless T-Bag is
他一定是把背包换了
He must've switched the packs.
那...?
wh-what do we do...
我们现在怎么办?
what do we do now?
这里还有5千美元
We still got the five grand we took
装钱的时候留下的
when we pocketed the money.
没有五百万那么多
It's not gonna be five million
但也足够我们到要去的地方了
but it might be enough to get us where we're going.
各单位注意
All units be advised.
福克斯河监狱的逃犯被确定
Escaped convicts from fox river have been positively ID'd
在蒙特里路1131号
at 1131 monterey lane
我们已经出动警犬进行搜索
We have dogs being dispatched to the location.
进出镇的每条路都封锁起来
I want every road in or out of town blocked off.
不管是汽车  火车  还是走路
I don't care if it's on wheels, rails or hooves.
都拦下来  仔细检查
I want it stopped and searched.
我记得你说过我们始终快他们一程
I thought you said we would have a head start.
是那枪声暴露了
It was the gunshot, buddy.
一定是被某个邻居听到了
One of the neighbors must've heard.
那东西能开多快?
How fast can that thing go?
不知道
I don't know.
我们俩的话  或许...
Both of us, it could probably...
我们不可能从马路走了
we're never gonna get out of here on the roads.
我们得想其他途径
We need to find another way.
伊利诺州  芝加哥   FBI办公室
Chicago, Illinois FBI Filed Office
他在你办公室了
He's in your office.
谁让他进来的?
Who let him in?
真难以置信这个节骨眼上把我招回
I can't believe they're calling me back here
那些逃犯都还逍遥法外
when my escapees are out there.
我想知道这个家伙是谁
I want to know who this guy is.
他说他叫萨林斯
Said his name was Sullins.
狗娘养的
Son of a bitch.
逃犯这边有什么进展马上通知我
Let me know if anything breaks on the convicts.
亚历克斯
Alex.
谢谢你能来
Thanks for coming in.
你能告诉我为什么内务部
You want to tell me why internal affairs is pulling me out of the field
在我追踪逃犯中途招回我?
in the middle of a manhunt?
好久没和你坐下来谈谈了吧?
It's been a while since we've had a sit-down, hasn't it?
自从肖逃走以来都没有过吧?
Not since the shales escape, am I right?
是的  到底怎么样  理查德?
Yeah, yeah. What's going on, Richard?
好吧...
Well...
这正是我来这的目的
that's precisely what I'm here to find out.
在我完事前你不能出去
And you're not getting out of here until I do.
怀俄明州  莱曼
Lyman, Wyoming
哦  天哪
Oh, my god.
人类的文明
Civilization.
要点什么?
What can I get for you boys?
你看呢
You tell me.
两杯水吧
Two waters, then.
知道你是好心人  让我用下电话吧
And the use of your phone, if you'd be so kind.
别担心  只打个市内电话而已
Don't worry, it's a local call.
我回家第一件事就是换条干净的内裤
First thing I do, we get home: Clean underwear.
然后呢?
Then what?
可能会回那个便利店
I guess go back to that liquor store
求他们让我继续干下去
beg for my job back.
我们曾有过机会
We had it.
可惜擦肩而过
We were so close.
我甚至还能依稀闻到那钱的味道
I can still taste that money right there in the back of my throat.
我现在不考虑别的
Well, nothing that a couple of Keystones
只想美美地吃上一顿汉堡肉饼
a hungry man salisbury steak dinner
然后坐在电视机前看看电视
and a night in front of the TV won't take care of.
嘿  妈妈  是我
Hey, mom, it's Brad.
我和罗伊的车子出了点问题
Hey, listen, me and Roy, we ran into some car trouble and...
你能否来接我们
we were wondering if you could come pick us up.
不知道  等一下
I don't know, hold on.
这该死的小镇叫什么?
What the hell town is this?
你不是说仅打个市内电话吗
Thought you said this was a local call.
嘿  布拉德利  看看这个
Hey, Bradley, check this out.
别挂  妈妈
Wait, mom.
据报道这些人就是
These individuals were reportedly the prisoners
几天前从伊利诺斯州福克斯河监狱逃出来的逃犯
who escaped from the fox river penitentiary in Illinois just a couple of days ago.
他们到底来犹他州的图勒镇做什么?
What were they doing all the way out here in Tooele, Utah?
根据珍妮特 欧文斯所说
Well, Jeanette Owens
她的车库被这些人挖开了
whose garage they dug up, has her own theory.
他们假装成电力公司的工作人员
They pretended that they were some kind of workers from the power company,
然后说这里有些问题
and that they had made a mistake
他们必须挖开修复
and they'd have to do some digging.
妈  我又想了想
Hey, mom, on second thought
你能不能给我们汇点现金?
uh, can you wire us some extra scratch?
事实上  我们还要办点事
Turns out, we ain't done yet.
你好
Hello.
布鲁斯  你得帮帮我
Bruce, I need your help.
莎拉?
Sara?
布鲁斯  我爸爸不是自杀的  知道吗?
Bruce, my father didn't commit suicide, okay?
冷静点  你在哪?
Okay, just calm down. Where are you?
他正在调查布伦斯的案子
He was looking into the Burrows case
我想他发现了一些
and I think that he found something
别人不想让他知道的事情
that they didn't want him to know.
我想现在他们认为我也知道了这些事
And now, I think that they think that I know it, too.
好吧  我要你听我说
All right, I want you to listen to me.
我派人来接你
I'm gonna send someone over to pick you up.
我先把你接回来 我保证我们一起把这事彻底解决
I'll bring you back here, and we'll sort all of this out, I promise.
告诉我你在哪里
Just tell me where you are.
我不知道  我在一个电话亭...
Uh, I don't know, I'm at a pay phone on...
第三大道和哈柏路的交叉口
Third and Harper.
你带手机了吗? 到时我可以联系你
Do you have your cell in case I need to reach you?
带了  但我想一定已经被监听了
Uh, I do, but I-I thought it would be tapped.
我不知道
I don't know.
好吧  我的人过去了
All right, someone's on their way.
待在那
Just stay right where you are.
谢谢
Thank you.
我出价80元
I'll give you 80 bucks for them.
不是吧  伙计 他们值...
Come on, man, they're worth...
对真正的主人来说
worth a lot more
当然远不止这个数
to the person they actually belong to.
这些是女子俱乐部的东西  伙计
These are ladies clubs, doctor.
我想她们比你那男人短裤
I'm guessing they're hotter
可要性感多了
than a monkey's jockstrap
80元
80 bucks.
加上那个冰块盒的话就成交
Throw in the cooler, and you got a deal.
我们必须丢弃这辆车了
We got to lose the bike.
不行
No way.
路都被封了
The roads are sealed.
这是我们从这里出去的唯一的办法
It's the only way we're gonna make it out of here.
老兄那我可办不到   我答应过皮提...
I can't, bro.I promised petey...
你不能把这辆车弄过河去
you're not getting that thing across the river.
我们浪费一分钟就少一分钟  明白吗?
And every minute we spend trying is a minute we don't have, okay?
对不起
I'm sorry.
我们得走了
We got to move.
我听说过这种地方
I've heard about these kinds of places.
有水蛭的  你知道吗
They got leeches, you know.
我宁愿被这里的水蛭咬
I'll take the leeches in here
也不愿被后面追兵拷住
over the handcuffs back there.
那可不好说啊
I don't know, papi.
要看这些水蛭咬什么地方
Sort of depends on where the leech leeches
-知道我说什么吗? -别开玩笑了
-you know what I'm saying? -Stop kidding around.
你还好吧  兄弟?
Are you all right, buddy?
我...我动不了了!
I can't... I can't move!
有什么地方受伤的吗?
You feel like you broke anything?
没有  我想应该没有
No, I don't think so.
能不能把这个?
Can you get it?
把它从我身上移走?
Can you get it off me?
一点都推不动
This thing's not going anywhere.
我下去看看你的脚
I'm gonna check your foot.
真不幸  伙计
I'm sorry, buddy.
卡住了
It's stuck.
你去打911
you, call 911.
凯莉  我叫莎拉 我是医生
Kelli, my name is Sara.I'm a doctor.
你会没事的  听得到我说话吗?
You're gonna be okay. Can you hear me?
你会没事的
You'll be all right.
深呼吸  然后...
Take some deep breaths and...
凯莉?
Kelli?
凯莉
Kelli.
会没事的  是吧?
It's gonna be okay, right?
我是说既然你能把我们八个人从监狱里弄出来
I mean, if you can get eight people out of prison,
当然也可以把我从这里弄出来 是吧?
you can get my puerto rican ass out of this, right?
可以吧?
Can't you?
加把劲!
Come on!
该死的!
Damn it!
听到了吗?
Do you hear that?
我知道那个声音
I know that sound.
河的上游有个坝
There's a dam up river.
这是个信号
It's a signal.
意味着他们开闸了
It means they're opening the locks.
这就意味着水面要上涨了
That means the water level's gonna rise
水面上升后
and when it does
这根木头就会漂走的
the log will just float right off.
真的?
Yeah?
警犬部队闻到了几种气味
Canine units at the scene have multiple scents
现正分头到田里搜索
and are spreading out into the field.
痕迹是刚留下的
Trail's fresh.
这几个家伙跑不远
These guys can't have gotten very far.
后面有6个人在搜那屋子
There were six cons back at that house.
他们会从各个方向来追捕我们
They'll be tracking us in every direction.
搜到这里得花上一个小时
It'll take an hour just to make it over this far
到那个时候  水面上涨  我们也早跑了
and by that time, the water level will rise, we'll be long gone.
你确定?
Are you sure?
是的  我肯定
Yeah, I'm sure.
我确定
I'm sure.
去问问当时在场的20个警察中的任何一个
Ask any of the 20 cops there,
约翰  阿布鲁奇是带着武器的
John Abruzzi was armed.
约翰 阿布鲁奇拿出了武器
John Abruzzi drew his weapon...
根本不该允许他走那么远
he never should have been allowed to get that far.
理查德  让我们说清楚
Richard, let's be clear.
如果你知道追捕逃犯应该怎样掌控局势
If you knew how things needed to be handled in a manhunt,
你就会让他逃跑
you'd be out there running one
而不是把他打瘸
instead of hamstringing the men that are.
FBI调查这起越狱事件的主要目标是
The FBI's primary objective in investigating fugitive matters
掌握他们的逃逸地点
is to affect the swift location
并抓住这些逃犯
and capture of the fugitives.
你已经杀了两个人了  亚历克斯
You have two dead bodies, Alex.
理查德 我只是杀了两个重刑犯
I've got two dead felons, Richard.
现在也许从公众关系的角度来说
Now, maybe that doesn't play well
这件事做得并不好
from a public relations standpoint,
但从公众安全这个角度上
but from a public safety standpoint
阿布鲁奇和阿克斯按常理是应该被杀的
Abruzzi and Apolskis were by the book.
近距离的向一个手无寸铁的小孩子射击
Shooting of an unarmed kid at point-blank range
也是符合常理的吗？
is by the book?
别狡辩了
Come on.
报告上说
Incident report
大卫 阿克斯
David "Tweener" Apolskis.
你知道  我很好奇 他在押送途中带手铐了吗？
You know, I'm curious, was he cuffed during transport?
是的
Yeah
这么说是他不知怎么
Says in here he somehow
成功地抢了你的枪
managed to grab your primary weapon.
-你的枪放在肩膀上的还是臀部上的枪套里? -臀部的
- You carry that in a shoulder holster? - Hip.
左边  右边?右边  左边?
Left, right? Right, left?
左边
Left.
对不起  我时常会搞混
I'm sorry, I get confused sometimes.
所以我可以这样推断
So just so I've got this right
你当时单独押着一个带着手铐的犯人开车
you were driving along alone with a cuffed prisoner,
然后不知怎的他袭向你的胸部
and somehow he reaches forward across your chest
抢了你的枪
and grabs your weapon.
很遗憾你和阿克斯在一起时
It's too bad you didn't react that quickly
反应还没有现在这么快
with Apolskis.
也许他还能活着
Maybe he'd still be alive.
有个计划可以解决所有问题
there's a plan to make all of this right
一只纸鹤能和这个有什么关系?
What does an origami bird have to do with any of this?
那是迈克尔・斯科菲尔德寄给她的
Michael Scofield sent it to her.
既然你为了平息事情
And since your brilliant plan
而打算把莎拉  唐克雷蒂除掉的杰出计划
to eliminate Sara Tancredi from the equation
-已经彻底失败了 -我不会说是彻底失败
-failed so completely -I wouldn't say it failed completely at all.
在电话亭里死了一个女人
There's a dead woman in a phone booth.
一个无辜百姓
Civilian.
你可以把一部分人的死归结于某人名下
A certain number of bodies you can sweep under the rug.
不过以总统的名义已经行不通了
President's rug is getting so full, you can hardly stand on it.
那你觉得我们该怎么做?
So what do you suggest we should do?
你钓过鱼吗  比尔?
You ever go fishing, Bill?
请说重点
Just make your point.
捕鱼有两种方法
There's two ways to catch a fish.
撒一张大网
You cast out a big
然后祈祷能得到你所想要的东西
net and hope you get what you're looking for.
要不你就得挑选合适的诱饵 并确保行之无误
Or you choose the right bait and guarantee that you do.
方法就是这么简单 世间万事也都如此这般
It's a simple strategy, plays across the board.
LJ会带我们找到布伦斯
LJ will lead us to Burrows.
莎拉会把我们引向斯科菲尔德
Sara will lead us to Scofield.
那你打算怎么跟踪莎拉?
And how do you intend to follow Sara,
她带给你的只有一直纸鹤
when the only lead you've got is an origami bird
和一个停机的电话号码
with an out of service phone number?
也许那根本不是电话号码
Maybe it's not a phone number.
你发现什么了?
What do you have?
那小鬼出来了  不过仍没有布伦斯的踪影
Junior's on the move, but still no sign of Burrows.
先生  那家伙藏匿起来了
Sir, the guy's in hiding
或许他还不知道儿子出来了
maybe he doesn't even know his kid's out.
犹他州那个被挟持的女警察已证实
The cop that was held hostage in Utah
在布伦斯得知LJ被释放后
has Burrows splitting off from the rest of the group
他就脱离他们那一伙了
just after word of LJ's release hit the wire.
他一定知道的
He knows.
现在如果想知道他到底在不在这儿
Now if we want to know for sure if he's there
我们得采取点行动把他引出来
we need to do something to draw him out.
给点零钱花花
Hey, you mind sparing some change?
没有
No.
给点吧
Come on.
没有  我身无分文
No, I'm all tapped out.
你一定有点什么
You got something.
我要拿走你身上的一切
I'll take whatever you got.
老实说  我刚被放出来 要是我有的话一定会给你
Look, seriously, I just got out of lock-up.
抱歉
Sorry.
我知道了  你觉得你比我强  是吧?
I see, you think you're better than me, huh?
我没觉得比你强
I don't think I'm better than you.
小子 你要往哪儿跑?
Yo, where you running, little man?
我哪也不去
I'm not running anywhere.
本不该这样的
This isn't how it's supposed to go.
我越狱只有一个理由
The whole reason I went along with the break
就是想和玛丽克鲁兹还有我的孩子共度此生
was to have a life with Maricruz and my baby.
而现在呢？
And now what?
找份普通工作
Get some two-bit job?
心平气和的看待一切?
Always be looking over my shoulder?
那种生活怎样?
What kind of life is that?
你可以和我还有林肯一起
You can come with me and Linc.
到巴拿马去
To Panama.
从头开始
Start over.
你待在这越久
The longer you stay here
就越没机会去巴拿马
the more chance there is you'll never make it to Panama.
你还有其他要牵挂的人
You've got other people to think about.
你哥哥  你外甥
Your brother, your nephew.
还有莎拉
Sara.
她会在巴拿马等你  对吧?
She's meeting you down there, isn't she?
我不知道
I don't know.
我们从没谈过此事
We never talked about it.
但你希望如此
But you're hoping.
这个等会再说  行吗
Just give it a rest, will you.
警犬们已经锁定住目标 我们还发现两条痕印合并一块了
The dogs are locked in. We've got two trails merging.
他们一定在这儿
They were definitely here.
他们往东边的爵克农场去了
They've headed east towards drucker ranch.
他们离开大路了  还需要人手
They've gone off-road.Any additional units
我们得形成一个一英里的包围圈
we need to setup a one-mile perimeter
然后开始缩小范围
and then start closing in.
水越来越深了
It's getting deeper.
这个烦人的玩意怎么还是一动不动的?
So how come this freaking thing ain't moving yet?
我来看看
Let me check
你还好吗？
You all right?
听着  迈克尔
Hey, Michael...
我明白如果你要继续走的话...
I understand if you have to keep going, you know.
别说那个
Don't say that.
我哪儿也不去
I'm not going anywhere.
不  还是想想吧
No, but, look, just think about it.
我不会让你就这么淹死
You know, if I leave you drown.
不  我知道  但是
No, I know, but just...
水面正在升高  苏克雷
the water level's getting higher, Sucre.
你能屏住呼吸多少秒?
How many seconds can you hold your breath?
45秒? 60秒?
45? 60?
如果我走了你就只能活那么久
That's how long you've got to live if I take off.
你呆在这又能有多久呢？
How long do you have if you stay?
在狗把警察带到这里以前还有多久?
How long till the dogs lead the cops here?
你提的建议都不可取
What you're suggesting is not an option.
听着  我并不想做个英雄或是什么
Look, I ain't trying to be a hero or nothing.
我们都知道现在只有两种情况会发生
We both know there are only two things that can happen now.
把我留在这儿
Leave me here...
或者两个都被捕
or we both get caught.
布鲁斯
Bruce.
莎拉
Oh, Sara.
我知道我们说好不用这个号码
I know we said not to use this number
但我想知道你是否安全
but I just needed to know you were okay.
我司机说他去接你
My driver said he went to pick you up
但那里是犯罪现场
and the place was a crime scene.
是的  他看到的那个女人 在电话亭边的那个
Yeah, the woman that he saw, the woman by the pay phone
本来应该是我
that was supposed to be me.
我  我只能把她留在那儿
And-and I had to leave her there.
我不知道该怎么办
I didn't know what to do.
布鲁斯  那些是什么人?
Bruce, who are these people?
他们清楚的知道我的方位
They knew exactly where I was going to be standing.
还知道我要去哪儿...
They knew where I was going to be...
莎拉
Sara?
是你
It was you.
你在说什么  莎拉?
What are you talking about, Sara?
我只是想知道你在哪儿
I just need to know where you are.
天啊
Oh, my god.
打扰一下
Excuse me
我想看看我们的朋友 LJ  布伦斯怎么样了
we'd like to check on a friend of ours, LJ Burrows?
他正在缝合伤口
He's getting some stitches.
我们只是想确定他安然无恙
We just want to make sure he's all right.
那他出来的时候你会看见的
And you can see him when he's through.
这是规定
It's policy.
你没搞清楚
You don't get it.
我很清楚  那个孩子是在自卫
I get that that kid defended himself.
你打算告诉我们为什么先袭击他吗?
You going to tell us why you attacked him in the first place?
-我已经告诉你了 -我知道  有人收买你做的
-I told you man. -I know, some guy paid you.
-有人付钱让我去做的 -打扰一下  FBI
-Some guy paid me to do it. -Excuse me. Fbi.
你说有人付钱让你这么做
What do you mean
此话怎讲？
somebody paid you?
见鬼  你觉得听起来会是什么意思?
What the hell does it sound like, man?
有个家伙给了我50美元
Some dude gave me 50 bucks
叫我揍那小子一顿
to give the kid a beat down.
是布伦斯  他在这儿
It's Burrows. He's here.
儿子  你感觉如何?
How you feeling, son?
爸爸
Dad?
我们得离开这
We got to move.
你知道的  你能做的不多
Well, there's not much you can do, you know.
打扰一下  女士们
Excuse me, ladies.
我有几个问题想问你
I need to ask you a few questions.
我是跟进调查组的
I'm on the, uh, follow-up investigation team.
麻烦一下
Excuse me.
我们只是想知道
Uh, we're just curious.
你是否看到那些罪犯找到了
Did you see if the convicts actually found
他们挖洞想找的东西？
what they were digging for?
没有  不过听上去好像找到了
No.But sure sounded like they did.
那个西班牙人
The spaniard
他非常兴奋的拿走了我女儿的一个露营背包
he took off with one of my daughter's camping packs
然后扔下其他人走了
and he left the other ones in a real tizzy.
听上去他用暴力手段背弃了他人
Sounded like he screwed 'em over something fierce.
然后他们就那么让他走了？
And-and they just let him leave?
他们是很不乐意  不过也没有办法
Well, they weren't happy about it, but, yeah.
他开着摩托离开了
He took off on his motorbike
几分钟后其他人也离开了
and then they left a few minutes later.
-一起走的? -不是
-Together? -No.
那个帅小伙和那个黑人先离开
The pretty one and the black fellow, they left first
再是那个邋遢的南方人
and then that dirty southerner...
他鬼鬼祟祟的从后门走的
he snuck out the back.
不过他行动有点缓慢
But he was moving kind of slow, you know
一来那个背包很重
the weight of that backpack
二来他本身还有伤残
and that disability that...
等等  他也有个背包?
wait a minute, he had a backpack, too?
是的
Yes.
他又倒回来  在出去的时候
He came back in and slipped this into my brassiere
把这个塞进我胸衣里
on his way out.
他说用这个来弥补我们的损失
He said it was to cover the damages.
我们要保留这个作为证据
Um, we're going to need to keep this as evidence.
谢谢合作
Thank you for your time.
上车
get the car
7 3 6 空格
Seven, three, six, space.
3 3 9 空格
Three, three, nine, space.
8 6 8 7
Eight, six, eight, seven.
你到底想查什么?
And what exactly are you looking for?
图形  代码
A pattern.A code.
任何东西
Anything.
是什么迈克尔? 你到底想要告诉我什么?
What? What are you trying to tell me, Michael?
听说...
They say...
一个人闯入你的生活总会有个理由
people come into your life for a reason.
也许我的理由就是帮你离开福克斯河监狱
Maybe my reason was to help you get out of Fox River.
帮你救出你哥哥
You know, to help you save your brother.
不是的
No.
没关系  兄弟
It's okay, papi.
不用管我
Let me go.
我们现在距离水坝下的小河1/4英里
We're a quarter mile up the river
他们就在附近
below the dam.
现在不走就来不及了  迈克尔
It's now or never, Michael.
我要你摒住呼吸
I want you to hold your breath.
-好不好? -为什么?
-Okay? -Why?
照做就是了
Just do it.
我保证马上就回来
I'll be right back, I promise.
你在搞什么鬼?
What the hell are you doing?
所有单位改道小河
all units to the river.
我要你潜下去
I want you to go under.
把手伸出水面  举高
And then stick your arm up, above the water, high.
好
All right.
如果你憋不住了
And then when you start running out of air
就前后挥动你的手
wave it back and forth
-这样我就能看到 -好
-so I can see it.
我就会过来救你
And I'll come back and get you.Okay?
明白了? 把你的手给我
All right, give me your hand.
1...
One...
2...
two...
快点  快点
Come on.Come on!
苏克雷
Sucre!
说吧
talk to me.
是这样
Well
有一个可能
there is one possibility
不过可能太简单了
but it's almost too rudimentary.
在看手机键盘的时候
We know we're not looking at a phone number
我们可能根本不会看它的数字
but maybe we're not looking at numbers at all.
而是看每个数字上面
What's important are the letters
对应的字母
that correspond to that number.
3个点  第3个字母
Three dots, third letter
R
"R."
2个点...D...E
Two-- "D," "E."
每个数字有3种可能
Three possibilities per number.
那就有成千上万种可能
That's thousands of letter combinations.
但是只有一种组合是对的
But only one of them's going to be right.
(rendezvous:约会地点)
rendezvous pendextoup
问题是地点在哪儿
Question is where.
你好
Hey.
你需要点什么?
What are you in the market for?
只要能开的车就行
Four wheels and a gas pedal.
嗨  皮特 是我
Hey, petey. Uh, it's me.
听着  我有点...
Uh, listen
事情要告诉你
I-I got something to tell you.
好的  我还在想你什么时候会打电话给我
Yeah, well, I was wondering when you were gonna call.
是的  上次见了你之后发生了很多事情...
Yeah, um, a-a lot has come down since we last talked, and, uh...
我知道  我听说了
Gee, I know, I heard.
你把它毁了
You ruined it.
是的  嗯...
Yeah.
你已经听说了?
you heard already?
老兄  所有人都听说了
Well, brother, everybody's heard, man
让我说些事给你听
and let me tell you something, man.
赫克托气坏了
Hector is pissed.
赫克托和这有什么关系?
What does hector have to do with it?
那是他的婚礼啊
It was his wedding.
等等  你在说什么?
Wait, man. What are you talking about?
你的摩托车啊  你说的又是什么?
Your bike.What are you talking about?
婚礼
The wedding.
婚礼怎么了?
What about the wedding?
你知道婚礼中说"我愿意"的那段吧?
Well, you know the part where, uh, you say, "I do"?
玛丽克鲁兹说"我不愿意"
Maricruz said, "I don't."
她真的这么说?
She did?
留下赫克托一个人站在圣坛上捧着罐头
Left homeboy standing at the altar holding his spam in his hand
如果你明白我在说什么的话
if you know what I'm saying.
你刚才说我的摩托车怎么了?
What were you telling me about my bike?
好的
All right.
我去拿钥匙给你
I'll go get your keys.
有两站要停
I got a couple stops to make.
第一个地方叫布兰丁
First is this place called Blanding.
-然后两天后我们和林肯会合 -我不能走
-Then we'll meet up with Lincoln in a couple days. -I can't go.
她说了"我不愿意"  兄弟
She said no, papi.
玛丽克鲁兹... 玛丽克鲁兹跟那个兔崽...
Maricruz...Maricruz told that son of A...
她跟他说她不愿意
she told him no.
你能相信吗?
Can you believe that?
太棒了
That's great.
我知道
I know.
现在
Now
我
I just...
不  去吧 把她找回来
No. Go on. Get your girl.
那巴拿马呢?  我们说好我们要...
What about Panama? We said that we were gonna...
另外找时间吧
Some other time.
巴拿马又不会跑掉
Panama's not going to go anywhere.
这个  在路上你如果遇到麻烦
This is, uh, in case you run into trouble
可以用的上
down the road.
在河里的时候
In the river...
我叫你别管我先走的
I told you to leave me behind.
是啊  我试过
Yeah, well, I tried
不过我被绳子缠住了  所以...
but, uh, then I got tangled up in the rope, so...
好了  钥匙给你
okay, here you go.
谢谢  还有...
Thanks, and, uh
我们还要一辆车
we'll need another car.
你真的认为那个恋童癖拿到了所有的钱?
Do you really think the diaper sniper got all of it?
只有一种办法才能弄清楚
Only one way to find out.
如果你是帝博格  你手上有5百万美元
If you were Bagwell, and you just got your hands on $5 million
你会去哪里?
where would you go?
你以为只有你才被别人背叛?
You think you're the only one who feels betrayed?
有一天我会从这里出去
I'm gonna get out of here some day.
那时候
And when I do
别以为我会忘记你家的前门是什么样子
don't think I won't remember what your front steps look like.
我直说吧
Let me get this straight.
是你付钱给那个家伙叫他揍我的?
You-you paid that Meth-Head to whoop my ass?
是啊
Yup.
联邦调查局的家伙正等着我来接你
Feds were waiting for me to come get you.
这是唯一的办法
It was the only way.
-成功了  不是吗? -是啊
-It worked, didn't it? -Yeah
是啊  让我缝了四针
it got me four stitches.
增加点个性
Adds character.
拿着
Here, take that.
里面有些冰块
There's some ice in there.
敷在眼睛上
Put it on the eye.
消消肿
Keep the swelling down.
我像你这么大的时候也打过一些架
I've been in a few fights in my day, too.
太多了
Too many.
rendez vous: 约会地点 sundown/hot: 日落旅馆
rendezvous sundown/hot
还有一张
There's one more bird.
清理一下
Clean it.
清除所有痕迹  要像她从没回过家一样
Every surface, like she never came home.
在等你从犹他飞回来的间隙里
You know, waiting for your flight from Utah
我稍微有了点空闲
I had a little extra time for due diligence,
于是我决定研究一下的你的过去
so I decided to dig a little deeper on your history
要不然还真不知道
or rather lack of one.
开始很简单  家境贫穷
Starts off simple enough.Poor family.
母亲由于家庭暴力离开
Mom leaves, cites spousal abuse.
不知何故你爸爸抚养了你
Somehow your dad holds onto custody, and
这些儿科医疗记录表明
by the look of these pediatric meds
随后四年他像打格陵兰海豹一样地打你
he beats you like a harp seal for the next four years.
很大的打击  穷困  虐待儿童   别无选择
Big shock-- poor, abused kid, not a lot of options
他参军了
he joins the military.
有什么想问就开门见山吧 别在那喋喋不休
Will there be any actual questions, or is this just a show-and-tell?
好  我有个问题
Okay, I got one.
为什么一个普通的步兵
How does a guy go from infantry grunt
作为特别观察员在第一次海湾战争表现平平
with less than stellar marks to the gulf 1, special ops,
却能加入联邦调查局
to the federal bureau of investigations
而且正领导着这个国家 有史以来最大的追捕行动?
leading the largest manhunt this country's ever seen?
我有这些零星线索
I have all these dots.
但是我却不能连系在一起
And there's just no way to connect them.
你应该查你职权范围内的事情... 迪克
Looks like you need to work on your clearance level...Dick.
或许我就想查你
Or maybe I just work on you.
-你想这么做? -我要把你锁在这张桌子上
-You want to do this? -I will chain you to this desk
直到我发现我的猜测是错误的
until I get some answers I cannot fertilize my lawn with.
你确定你真的要这么做?
You sure you want to do this?
我知道他们让你在国外做了什么  亚历克斯
I know what they tell you to do overseas, Alex,
让我把话再说得更清楚点
and let me make it perfectly clear
在美国国土上我们不能那样做
we do not do it on American soil.
长官  有电话找你
Sir, uh, there's a phone call for you.
我等一下再接
I'll take it later.
长官  你最好现在就接
Uh, sir, you're gonna want to take this now.
喂
Yeah.
是  长官
Yes, sir.
我...
I, uh...
我现在就和他在一起
I'm with him now.
是 长官
Yes, sir.
好
Okay.
你去哪儿?
Where you going, Rick?
我想我们应该进入正题了
I thought we were really starting to get somewhere.
我们走
Let's go.
亚历克斯
Alex.
你有什么给我?
You got something for me?
打开它
open it.
这些数字联系到
The numbers correlate
手机上的字母
to the letters on a phone.
只有这个可能
Only on this one
其他组合都说不通
none of the possible combinations make sense.
我们认为这数字对应的是个地点
We think it's a location
迈克尔 斯科菲尔德约定的见面地点
a rendezvous point for Michael Scofield.
找到了地点
You find it
就找到了他
you find him.
你该快些把我从那里弄出去
You know, you could have gotten me out of there sooner.
我们需要通过些渠道
You know, even we have to go through certain channels
才能把事情做得看起来可信
to make things appear on the up-and-up.
亚历克斯你明白这些  不是吗?
You know all about that, don't you, Alex?
保持原样吧
Keeping up appearances.
很好
Good.
我只是想确认一下
I was just making sure
你是否还记得这次追捕的目标
that we're still clear on the directive of this manhunt.
我知道...追捕布伦斯和斯科菲尔德的原因
You know, I understand the, uh, reasoning behind Burrows and Scofield,
但是其他人...虽然他们可能是罪犯
but these other men-- criminals that they may be--
但是没有证据表明...
there's nothing in their profiles to suggest...
你只是被雇佣做事的
you've been hired to do a job.
理由不关你的事
The reasoning does not concern you.
不要问关于我们的问题
Don't ask any questions about us
这样或许我们能继续保证不再有人调查你
and maybe we'll continue to make sure no one asks any questions about you.
明白了吗?
Are we clear?
全部都得死
They all die.